hello I'm your host David Barnard and
with me today Revenue cat CEO Jacob
biting Our Guest today is Martine
sinowski co-founder and CEO of podcast
app after bootstrapping streama into one
of the largest radio streaming services
in the world our team founded podcast
app to help enhance the joy and personal
growth provided by podcasts on this
podcast we talk with Martine about
spinning off a new product from
secondary product Market fit the Journey
of getting into YC and to give and take
of raising venture capital
hey Martin thanks so much for joining us
on the podcast today really excited to
be here thanks for having me on and
Jacob always nice to have you on an
episode I'm here for the folks on the
video pod this is the first time in the
enhanced studio with the neon backdrop
and all that stuff you'll have to check
out the YouTube yeah check it out on
YouTube Jacob has a really nice neon
Revenue cat logo in the background this
is a trick it's not actually neon do you
know that they don't do neon seriously
it's just yeah I mean LEDs we're living
in the world you know it's the air of
solid state so everything's just you
know it looks like neon it looks much
more exactly it looks like we have much
more affordable anyway we're here to
talk about subscriptions
all right so Martine I want to talk
about your app podcast app but before we
get there you started your career in
apps with an app called streama and
combined between streama and podcast app
you're not 100 million downloads which
just blew my mind when you told me that
so tell me about bootstrapping streamoff
first and kind of know what the app is
and what led you to build it and then
we'll get into the podcast app and
everything else today sounds great yeah
it still blows my mind too to think of
like 100 million downloads numbers in
the thousands or hundreds of thousands
it's already quite impressive when you
come to think of like 100 100 million is
beyond human yeah yeah it's pretty crazy
to grasp yeah yeah so the story with
streamer so it's a am and FM radio
streaming service right so if you want
to listen to our radio station from any
country in the world any city in the
world you can do it through our service
and before it was an app it was actually
a website the website is still pretty
big and we started that in 2007 and so
it was a long arduous experience I
thought I was gonna get a Lamborghini
after a couple of years it ended up
being like four years of complete no
Revenue no payments no users no nothing
and then slowly very slowly things
started to happen and we only launched
the app which is called Simple radio
which is the one that has lots of
installs as we're talking many years
after that probably like 2013 so we kind
of I came late into the game of mobile
but it's been a company it's been around
like 15 16 years it's profitable I
haven't been personally involved writing
it in the past six years since I've
started building podcast app but it was
where I learned and made most of my
mistakes and uh it's always good to have
a starter company you know yes yes
ideally you know it's even better if
it's not yours that's what I did but
this is a good tactic and it's kind of a
recurring theme of folks who we've had
on who bootstrapped is that there's this
kind of idealism of I'll start my side
project and it's going to instantly
become this hit but yeah it sounds like
you wandered in the desert for years
before it actually made a meaningful
Revenue we did wander in the desert for
years and we had some false starts it
almost looked like it's gonna happen and
it didn't quite I'm kind of dating
myself but at this point we were like
using the Facebook platform you know and
they were like oh yeah yeah like it was
708 yeah yeah yeah totally yeah so we
first started like a social network for
radio listeners 2007 Facebook for
everything right so we started doing
that nothing can happen then they
announced the apps and their platform
and we started hearing these Wild West
stories so yeah oh it was a lot less you
could do it wasn't really anything yeah
it was really wild west not super proud
of the things that happened in there
just to give people like concrete like
you could crawl the Facebook API you
could just jump from person to person
Cambridge analytica is nothing compared
to what you could do in like 2007. for
us it was like there were like
notification apis you could use to like
send notifications it's amazing right
you come to think of it it's kind of
crazy like you could actually send
notifications on behalf of Facebook for
your app right these were important
notifications because they weren't in
the phone but they were still in that
desktop app right there was a small
window before you know when Farmville
and all those people exploited it until
Facebook shut it down it was only like
totally exactly exactly so we I think we
caught for months of that and we did
have some dazing which we had like 130
000 daily actives new users through this
kind of crazy viral Loops but we have
quotas and they will close the quotas
and they will like reset back after 20
days or 30 days you had to wait for the
next big boost of users the problem was
they ended up shutting it down and also
the users were coming from countries
that were monetizing great so it wasn't
like U.S users or some of those really
well monetizing countries so I think
that at the peak we made hundred dollars
in ad Revenue not the most encouraging
so that was one of the false starting
which we thought we were seeing the
light and we didn't quite see it but
slowly and surely we started figuring it
out that was the first experience and as
I was saying like it's been profitable
for the past five six years and operated
by an amazing team independently and
it's been really good I did want to
transition to the podcast app so you
built streamer it's doing really well
you finally get the momentum going what
made you decide to jump from that to
build the podcast app masochism
because otherwise I Cry
this whole thing is really a mind game
right you really need to I think laugh
at it and also this whole journey of
understanding oneself better and what
were the things we do I mean at the time
and it's still our motivation so we had
this amazing 10-year run with srima
after 10 years I co-founders and folks
on the team you start becoming a
different person wanting different
things maybe thinking about what's your
next stage what's your next phase and
how you want to do it and we all have
different ideas for me and also for whom
we ended up being my co-founder in
Pakistan who was our CTO at streama his
name is Juan College mate of mine we
kind of had this desire of building like
a bill to last company we had read this
book actually by Jim Collins right the
bill to last and they talk about
long-lasting enduring companies and
companies with a purpose and with strong
core values and that idea kind of
resonated with us I think we were doing
a little bit of soul searching with
srima and many other things happened we
personally got into podcasts because
they were the future of radio from live
to On Demand analog to digital that sort
of thing and we were enamored by
podcasts just this idea of learning from
the world's greatest Minds being able to
obtain knowledge while you're doing
something else that maybe it's not
particularly fun or meaningful like
washing the dishes or just driving
somewhere we started talking with the
idea of putting all these things
together and also felt like there was
going to be a big migration from radio
and other media idioms onto podcasts and
that was 2016 and there had already been
a few like let's say boom and busts
around podcasts but I'm trying to
remember when when was cereal what year
was that serial I'm guessing like 2014
okay there's like false yeah right
because podcasting's been around like I
remember downloading podcasts in like
2006. yeah right but it was like before
super nerdy you had to do it in iTunes
right or an RSS feed and there were very
few people that was the technology I
just felt like we were in the flats for
a very long time but then this period
you're talking about there were just
convergence of big money came in like
cereal New York Times like those started
to come into it I guess also it was just
like a consumer Behavior thing right
like normies for lack of a better word
had to understand downloading digital
and it had to change from being RSS
feeds of MP3s to being like a click
button get audio content model right but
that would have been right around that
time so yeah yeah I think there were
like many different pillars and that
were being built or assembled from like
content to user interface even like more
penetration maybe not a devices like
Android cultural moments like serial
which is ties back into content but
there was for example Stitcher Stitcher
was a big one right big app that they
actually raised like 30 million I think
it was like around 2012 2013 they had
already raised a significant amount of
money and funny enough I ended up
meeting the founder of Stitcher we ended
up becoming friends and he was like the
first advisor to podcast up and I
randomly made an event here in San
Francisco but yeah I think it was these
conversions of things you know
opportunity and trends that we were
identifying a personal passion and a
desire of thinking hey can we build
another company make it larger bigger
maybe more purposeful and having more of
an impact in the world and hoping
something that can be our last company
and maybe the last thing I want to say
is I was living in Argentina at the time
that's where I'm from originally and I
also kind of had this desire I don't
know of playing in the big leagues and
doing it from Silicon Valley and doing
that sort of experience we had also felt
some pain with strima even though we
built it to like pretty large company
and it's the second largest platform for
that AM FM radio world the first company
was built from here and we were doing it
from Argentina bootstrapping it for the
US right so I was gonna ask like I
didn't know if you guys use Latin
America as like a wedge or if it was
fully based U.S or so definitely Brazil
is a big country for the product but U.S
is the main one in terms of Revenue and
the most important metrics so when you
founded podcast app did you initially
bootstrapper or you go straight to
raising a little bit of funding we tried
to race and we failed quite a bit
turns out that moving to a different
country and here right to this ecosystem
and maybe having us one of your
accolades that you bootstrap something
even if the scale is pretty interesting
it's not that meaningful or important
it's not one of the classic I think
pattern matching that people use you
know it's almost an anti-signal to them
right they're like yeah oh great you
built a cash flowing business that's not
dependent on Capital like what do I get
yeah
yeah exactly exactly like you're looking
for money to do this again so that was
tricky we did try to raise money at the
beginning we did a few different things
you know like we applied to YC that was
part of the dream YC that'd be awesome
we were reading all the program essays
for the past 10 years so we applied at
the end of 2016 rude awakening we got to
the interview stage but we got
obliterated in the interview stage with
some like really where did they hit you
guys like what weren't you I'm sitting
down in my chair and they start like
another podcast player we have iTunes we
have apple it works great like why do I
care about this what is this you know
like I have really bad copying it big
time did you not know that that's what
the style of the interview is going to
be or I think I knew some extent but I
just hadn't fully internalized like kind
of I think penetrated my defenses more
than it should have and it's starting us
on the wrong foot I think we were still
fresh in many respects had you built
anything at that point was the app live
on yeah when you first applied so over
2016 we built like a first prototype
within streamer you know we were already
exploring podcasts within srima and we
were wondering like are we gonna do it
within srima is it going to be a
separate company and we ended up
speeding it off funny enough we started
with Android so it was only like an
Android I'm saying funny enough because
in the US most monetization at least
what we've seen is happens through iOS
right so we started with Android we had
early Revenue we had some decent level
of traction and we had the streamer
background and we got to the interview
stage close enough right I think it's
500 folks or companies getting invited
to that so pretty close but yeah we just
got obliterated there and we just hadn't
had that much exposure pitching
investors you know we just not something
that we were used to because we were
more in our own bubble and ecosystem
building our own bootstrap thing for 10
years and immediate exposure I guess to
investors so we raised some money from
stream our co-founders we put in some
money ourselves we started doing that we
didn't have a lot of Runway but also we
didn't have a lot of costs it was
stressful my wife and I had moved here
cost of living expenses you know coming
from Argentina like 5x 10x I don't know
what what happens you know and all of a
sudden time is taking and I think we had
a mixture of scale and luck honestly in
the sense that somewhat fast we were
able to get traction many of the things
we were doing that we learned from the
stimulates cannot translate it well you
know when it comes to user acquisition
and distribution and monetization so
very fast we were able to start
generating building an audience and
growing eventually we got into YC it was
another year had the second interview go
you come in much better much better
I felt like I'm a big Rocky Balboa fan
and I just felt like it was the rematch
you know oh yeah classic Arc right yeah
yes if I feel like it was the rematch we
were pumped we were in a different
mindset we tend to be very chill people
you know very thoughtful and we hear
people loud you know here we were ready
more for a fight yeah it's interesting
the interview is I don't know what their
exact philosophy of it but it's 50
Constitution and intelligence tests
right they want to just see how fast you
are on your feet maybe only half of it's
Pro being the idea and your preparation
if they can defeat your idea in 30
seconds or 10 minutes then like you're
not ready right you need to be ahead and
you made some point there about building
stream uh like kind of on your own and
sort of your own bubble and when folks
are considering this like bootstrap not
whatever I do think that outside capital
or outside pressure can be really
helpful for a company I found it really
helpful for me when I'm not sure what to
do next or like not sure how fast I go
or how slow to go whatever having a
little bit of that constraint or
interactions with those investor types
or whatever I found can be really
clarifying it forces a little bit of
discipline right it forced you to go
back and clarify your thinking and
really be able to defend your idea did
you have the same interviewer both times
they probably don't remember different
interviewers but the second one was
tough it was Michael siebel wow I'm sure
they're all tough I don't think I've
never heard anybody say like I Breeze
through it so I don't have to do too
much YC inside baseball but yeah it's an
intense experience I've never been in a
more loaded atmosphere than like sitting
outside the interview rooms like I've
never seen so many nervous overachieving
kids in my life outside of the YC and
you'll get all sorts of Dynamics and
Vibes the first time I remember like
some folks started interviewing me or
like reading me on my phone I was
out in the hallway because I was so
nervous it's so silly now but like I
brought my mother-in-law so they give me
some like peppermint smelling oils that
were like supposed to be calming you're
just supposed to put a little bit on
like your body and then you smell and
it's just but no I just brought the
whole bottle with me and the whole time
I was just like you were drinking it
just like it like a crazy person
one thing you talked about in the first
interview was them pressing you on well
apple has a podcast app Google has a
podcast app Spotify I don't know if they
were big in podcasts at the time you
applied but this is a huge deal for apps
like how big can your app really be
there may be a huge tan but it's also
super competitive going into that second
interview did you prep for that question
or how did that go and how do you think
about it even to this day like how big
can the podcast app be that's a really
good question so there's you say yeah
bootstrap versus bench you're back and I
think this idea of deciding how to do it
or what to go goes beyond like the
market size I think it's also like a
matter of what you're signing up for you
know when what kind of entrepreneurial
Adventure you want to go through we're
coming right off at coming off this
bootstrap so let's have that
conversation right so like okay did you
guys know because I think that was the
thing I didn't know honestly even when
we did YC it clarified to me during YC
what you're signing up for you go from
building cash flow business first to
building an equities business first
you're engaging in business with some
people who you know essentially invest
in equities for a living right just like
any other customer they're going to like
spend some money and expect some kind of
return did you know that or I mean I'll
say for me I think I was stuck in the
lights a little bit right I was like
this is what you do this is what all
these Founders I look up to do like
where were you at in that mental game I
think it was mixed feelings I definitely
was thinking a lot about it because we
were very jaded or skewed I guess by a
10-year bootstrapping experience and so
we were constantly thinking should we
have done it differently is this a
better path so I definitely was thinking
a lot about it and to this day I still
think a lot about it because we've
raised some money we raised like a
million and a half so we didn't raise a
lot of money and that option is still on
the table for us it's not that we said
hey we're never going to raise money
again but I just wonder will that be the
best path so at the time yes we were
thinking about it I think one of the
main worries for us was is this
something that's going to compromise our
desire to build something for the future
that can last is it going to limit our
options too much is it going to
compromise our lifestyle the heroes
these horror stories I love working hard
and I do think that work is my hobby to
some extent so I'm sure it's kind of sad
no no it makes sense I'm happy but I
don't feel like there's some kind of
craftsmanship around being an
entrepreneur and Building Things but at
the same time I want to have my family I
want to do certain things that are
important to me and so I guess I was
afraid and after hearing all these
stories of folks getting burned out
things that sounded terrible but here's
what I would say for sure the more you
bring outside folks right involving
other people in the business I think
there's higher Stakes there's more
responsibility there's more
accountability I think what you're
saying earlier Jacob right you need to
know if you're in the mood for that
right and if that's what you want to
sign up for or if you want to do
something that's more your terms you
your freedom optionality always again I
don't want to get too like into the
psychology but I do think there's the
issue of commitment how comfortable do
we all feel in commitment versus freedom
I think there's lots of parallels there
I've never really had a bootstrapped
business I think everybody grasses
Greener right they're always thinking
that the other one is oh that'll solve
all my problems in reality it's
somewhere messy middle I think the
easiest thought process I'll give to
most folks is that you know with raising
Venture it unequivocally accelerates
your business right like you can make
the higher today you would have had to
wait a year right you can build the
thing today that you would have had to
wait and that can make the whole thing
go a lot faster assuming you can find
product Market fit and you're actually
building into a market that cares The
Venture Capital can be really really
awesome and you don't have to build a
wholly unhealthy business too right like
you can just be you know like Revenue
cat we operate maybe a year ahead of
what we can afford right at any given
time or so plus or minus depending on
the quarter yeah we burn Venture but
also like the business is sound in a lot
of ways I think the thing that I always
think about is that once you bring that
money in you're limiting your options
the number of all mutually agreed upon
successes for the company is limited
right doesn't mean you're screwed
doesn't mean you can't do certain things
right like there are stories of
venture-backed companies that have
returned to like a free cash flow and
bootstrapping model there are stories of
companies that have I don't know I think
Kyle's been pretty public about this but
like gumroad is a good example like he
raised a bunch from I think the Sequoia
and never really got the right product
Market fit and he just kind of went to
him he's like hey I'm just not gonna
keep building this like you guys want
and they kind of just cashed out they
were like yeah okay that's fine right
they wrote it off and then he's gone and
built it his own way right so there are
options but those can be rare my advice
would be it's a bit reductive but I
think it's true it's like when you take
money from people just figure out how
you're gonna pay them back 5 10 20x like
that's what they're going to want that's
their success criteria is a 5 10 20x
payday and if you're not comfortable
thinking about that math
then probably don't take the money right
and I saw this and it was helpful for me
it's like I was very timid about it
initially I was like I don't know like
it's so scary and I think seed and early
stage investors are very good at kind of
being like nah you know pushing a little
bit like yeah yeah you just take this
deal it's not a big deal but as you get
further along like it gets a little bit
they're like I do want to return at some
point right like especially if you start
to look like a winner and that goes back
to that accountability it can be good I
think for me it's been good it's not
just the advice that I get from this
folks it's the betting and them saying
folks I know have other winners and
being like I think you have the makings
of a winner in our portfolio so like I
want you to keep pushing I find that
helpful but I also for Revenue cat I
couldn't be like 180 actually we're
going to be a bootstrap totally now like
that's been viable anymore which is fine
it's okay in life to close doors
sometimes I just I think the advice that
I would hope anybody in this situation
that's the thing you need to think about
is like okay what doors am I closing and
am I okay closing those doors I don't
think there's like a right answer I mean
we covered this on the podcast before
but it's rare to talk to somebody who's
played both sides I think that's a great
summary man I also do Wonder again this
might be an example of classic screener
on the other side but I do wonder if
there's like a b2c versus B2B difference
also oh absolutely yeah like I look at
the feeling of course b2e companies they
pivot they struggle with prior Market
fit all of these classic surprises I
think that all companies have but I do
feel like b2c I don't know that's all my
experience right that's all I've done
and it's like I don't know you're trying
to kind of read the culture a little bit
you know what's going to happen in the
world broadly I mean we all do that as
entrepreneurs but I do think that
there's something here that it's less
predictable more artistic maybe like
yeah it's a hits business right if you
look at other hits businesses like the
movies they run a portfolio like having
lots and lots of movies and they lose a
lot of money on a lot of movies and then
they have a couple that make a ton and I
think what that does is it creates this
really dangerous and difficult early
phase where you haven't had your first
hit yet and you know with B2B
if you can make one customer happy like
truly happy you have a foothold and then
you can make that too and you can make
that for and like that's how we met like
I met you during YC when I was looking
for those first couple of customers to
make happy I emailed you because you're
when I see I was like can I just come
put my stupid SDK in your app please and
you were gracious enough to be like sure
and we hung out in a blue bottle for a
few hours you send some pull requests
for us like including the SDK but I
think it was obviously a couple of bucks
you know sometimes your car fixed they
ever put some like candy on the dash or
a little bit of like appreciation gift
that was my little appreciation gift I
fixed some UI things I saw while I was
in there and it was really cool man by
the way because subscription wasn't big
for us at the time right now it's most
of our revenue and the company 3x or 4X
because we properly took the time to
like focus on subscription and at the
time it was mostly ads and subscription
was something that we had but just for
the handful of people that wanted to
remove the ads and so we gave them a
subscription that was pretty hidden and
it was already working and I think you
added the SDK so we would do it through
you but it ended up like planting the
seeds for what would be truly the future
of our business model and our Revenue so
I won't take any credit at all for that
I will take credit for fixing the little
launch UI bug though like the image
being missized that definitely I take
credit for but that era you know go back
to the B2B b2c as a B2B founder you can
show up to a coffee shop and Implement
and learn and iterate and like there's
just much easier toe holds and then like
the flywheels are present much sooner in
a B2B business also because of retention
our retention tends to be over 100 it's
just an easier game and so going into
that question I would say is actually an
easier game but in some ways more
predictable game and so going back to
the raising question I've definitely
changed my attack here a lot and I think
for Consumer Founders I think it's even
a bigger gamble with B2B it's been
pretty well shown how Venture Capital
can be turned into like Enterprise
Equity value and then eventually like a
public company for b2c they certainly
exist I mean there's duolingos of the
world there's lots of b2c and they're
massively valuable I mean compared to
even like your average B to B company in
a lot of ways but there's an order of
magnitude or several orders magnitude
fewer of them there are so and even
Duolingo right I feel like it's so much
more clearly at like a educational tool
to learn a very concrete skill which is
amazing and I think it's an amazing
company right but I'm just compare that
to maybe like a clubhouse the race I
think I don't know was it a billion like
100 billion yeah they raised more money
than four billion and killed the company
essentially right it put them in a
really weird place at the time they were
really booming the metrics were insane
we were following it because we are in
the audio space plate and we were like
whoa and it looked like it could be the
next big thing right and then maybe I
don't know lockdowns is covered change
defensive things and I don't know the
exact metrics but from public analytics
you can see that they have come way down
and as you're saying like raising so
much money limits your optionality where
do you go from there when you raise so
much money you need to do like a 10x
15x20x out of that it's really tough
even for a company that was all already
with huge amount of traction and things
can change rapidly that's kind of how I
see a little bit difference between b2c
and B2B taking back the entire
conversation we've been having this last
piece think through the implications of
like either path there's no right or
wrong paths it's more about thinking
through the implications or doing it
either way and maybe try to see which
one's the best for you and I don't think
raising money necessarily means that
it's not like such a binary decision I
guess the raising money peace because I
think it's the more you raised and the
further yeah exactly before it comes up
every incremental dollar like the floor
of possibilities gets cut off and
there's some categories of exits that
kind of get smaller with time so
circling all the way back I am really
curious in that second interview because
again I think so many consumer apps like
we've talked through now all the reasons
you would or wouldn't raise money and
opportunity and everything else like
that but for those who are thinking they
might want to raise money you do have to
when talking to somebody who's going to
invest convince them at some level that
there's enough opportunity to be Venture
scale that they will be able to get a 5
10 20x return on that investment so
going into that second interview and
then especially kind of knowing the
first interview part of why that went
South was that Apple has a podcast app
Google has a podcast app how did that
second interview go as far as convincing
them that you were potentially a venture
scale outcome I think the interview
specifically they weren't necessarily
about size of Market the first interview
I'm going to write off just because I do
feel like we kind of froze you know I'm
gonna Broke Down Under Pressure the
second one so the other person was
Gustav who used to be the head of growth
at RBM who's our group partner as well
yeah yeah we work with him and with
Michael and I think they were both
Believers around streaming and around
the audio itself and by the way when we
didn't get in for the first batch of YC
three months after that Tech Ranch
article announcing all the startups
there was another podcast company with a
very similar pitch to ours I think that
what that means is that they were
Believers in podcast to the point that
they were already backing a company
talking about market for a moment some
ways of thinking about it at least in
the case of podcasts one way was looking
at Radio the broadcast radio world hobby
of an industry in ad Revenue that is and
that will stand 13 billion something
like that and what was the time spent
listening on talk radio which is like
comparable to podcasts I think that was
25 so with that you could already see
like hey there's multiple billions right
a year that are spent on ad Revenue just
locked up in a legacy yeah exactly
without targeting without any type of
intelligence and the content also is not
personalized right like the audio
content that folks are listening to so
podcasts will be much more compelling so
that was already like one way of
thinking about it but I think what YC
was more interested at the time and I
can see that was the subscription angle
and there was a lot of talk at the time
of building the Netflix or podcasts so
in that case it was more like a Bottoms
Up approach kind of saying okay how many
subscribers would we need for this to be
like 100 million dollars a year type of
business and the math added up just in
the sense that it was maybe like
millions of subscribers yeah it's not
huge yeah yeah it's not huge right when
you see like Spotify or Netflix the
scale they're at I think now there's
been more attempts at that from luminary
like it's a company that started with
that page they raise 100 million out of
the day they had like 50 premium shows
and they never quite were able to do
that or scale it and Spotify itself
right that's it so far they've been like
big winners in the world podcast but
they invested more than a billion
dollars into doing that there was only
one moment in history when you could
invest a billion dollars in like exactly
podcast content and they did it when
they could right yeah yeah well for them
it was content but it was also like
platform you know like hosting Services
ad targeting services and then the
content and Deals and networks I guess
there's different approaches how to do
that estimation of the market right now
we're doing something actually in the
world of sleep and we recently had to do
that too same exercise you mean just
yeah same exercise of like yeah I think
the more and more you grow as an
entrepreneur or maybe you get older the
more you realize that hey the size of
the market matters it's really hard to
build something that wins anywhere might
as well maybe do it in a large Market
where there's lots of money flowing and
so we did that recently for sleep and
yeah let's talk about that so yeah
you've run the podcast app and then I'll
cut the story short you initially were
more focused on ads and then really
double down in subscriptions and have
been very successful growing it as a
subscription business also I just want
to point out the all-time greatest name
of a company ever which is to name it
the SEO perfect name right it's like A1
podcast app that you put in the phone
book right by the way I would love to
give you like a really inspirational
like we did this workshopping session
this Retreat you know off the grid for
five days and we came up with that but
it was actually in the Stream uh like
within streamer we had to launch the
Prototype I think for Android and we
have to put a name on Google Play and I
don't know someone on our team came up
with said the podcast app it's so good
it's so good I mean it's something
forward it's probably gonna help with
SEO or something if you'd gone to the
stupid Retreat you would have come up
with some name that wasn't even in where
words and like nobody's gonna remember
right the podcast app so good it does
create sometimes have you downloaded the
podcast app it's like well which box
yeah yeah but then you get a really nice
moment where you like the podcast app
right it's like the titular anyway yeah
yeah yeah so the podcast app is doing
really well but recently you did decide
to become a multi-product company talk
us through that exercise in both
thinking through becoming a
multi-product company and then with the
Sleep product that kind of Market
Discovery yeah so Pakistan we got it to
like 130 000 page subscribers so that's
number we're pretty proud of but yeah
talking about multi-product company I
think my first rule of multiply
companies is trying not to become a
multiplier company
the masochism yes yes now because there
is this issue of focus I think for us it
came from a place of hey we've been at
this for like six years now with the
podcast app we got it to meaningful
scale but what's the next PATH forward
for us and we had a team of 20 folks
highly capable people how do we use our
time in the best possible way and
continuing with this idea of building
large businesses but also in a way that
has positive impact which Stills
continues to be a through line for us
since those days at Tremont starting
into a Pakistan right so we came up on
this opportunity on sleep it wasn't like
a systematic approach for like some
folks can be very regimented in
exploring opportunities and really
opening up the aperture and lens there's
a backstory of lots of experiments that
we did within podcast app that didn't
necessarily pan out in terms of like
where can we meaningfully differentiate
Beyond like the essence of podcasts and
we trade like experiments around
education from creating our own content
to like creating thematic playlists with
editors and curators to creating like a
social podcasting learning Club kind of
like a book club you know over WhatsApp
like I mean we did all sorts of crazy
things in this past few years with the
goal of exploring what's the next big
leaping growth while doing all of this
we came up across the use case of sleep
podcast for sleep we were seeing lots of
people using our app at night for sleep
and it turns out podcasts can have a
hypnotic effect hopefully not hours
because ours is very engaging but but
other podcasts can have a bit of a
hypnotic effect and so people like
forget what about their concerns what
happened during the day you know and
they're able to like fall asleep similar
to maybe reading a book but without
light in your face for some people it
works better we started looking into
sleep we also went through our own
personal Journeys with sleep you know
being stressed as entrepreneurs I also
had a my first daughter two years ago
and so different experiences with sleep
and we learned a lot we did all sort of
weird experiments from like cooling down
or my mattress to like looking like at
work at night with the blue light
Blossom classes you know or wearing the
ordering for many years so kind of
similar thing to podcasts we saw some
like adjacent type of opportunity we
have personal experience and again we
started looking into a space and it does
look like there's a huge amount of
people with sleep problems it's only
getting worse and the money that's being
spent is really big like it's huge in
the US it looks like 30 billion a year
multiple categories of course from the
sleep medication to like the mattresses
we started doing interviews with people
who had improved their sleep and it
turns out that usually people they buy
lots of products in many different sub
categories of the market because they're
trying to for them it's about improving
their sleep and getting it solved you
know they don't care they don't think oh
I'm only gonna buy a mattress I'm a
mattress purchaser you know stick here
you know big mattress person you know
yeah
exactly so because there's some
controversy sometimes you know in terms
of like okay what's really the market
that you can you're not building a
mattress yeah you're building a mobile
app are you going to take loaders away
from mattresses are you going to capture
any of that value or not and I think
there is an opportunity of doing that
because it just help people sleep better
baby have less of a need for buying
other products or maybe you can be the
person who directs them to buy the right
product for them that's going to help
them America capture some of the value
there that's kind of how we came to this
new opportunity in sleep that we're
pursuing started with audio we started
as we learned more getting into using Ai
and specifically like llms to give
people like a personalized sleep
coaching experience because a lot of
that has to do with changing your habits
and changing your routines and changing
your thinking around sleep and it's not
easy to do like some people go to
doctors but they're expensive or hard to
find or other folks they just do it
themselves by listening to podcasts and
watching videos and being on Tick Tock
and learning where and then trying an
error so yeah we're trying to create
something that solves it better and
faster for people sounds like with the
podcasts app you were looking for that
second level product Market fit like we
were talking about with competing with
Google and Spotify and apple and
everyone else like how much money is
there in podcasts app and what are the
opportunities so it's really cool that
through trying to find that second level
of product Market fit with the podcast
app that you actually came upon the
Sleep opportunity and then also just
even looking at how much more
willingness there is to pay and all of
those kind of opportunities but now
you're a two Product Company how has it
gone and the sleep app has already
launched how did you get those early
users for the sleep app yeah I wish we
had another three hours to talk through
all the distribution and the things that
you did with both srima and the podcast
app and now the third app like you've
kind of run the gamut but yeah give us a
speed run of what it was like
bootstrapping inside an already
successful company this new app this
secondary product I don't think we'll
share like this Vision that distribution
is extremely important you've always
been really good at acquiring users I
think you've been one of the founders I
think's always been just very
comfortable doing that yeah I think the
most important piece is to have folks
realize first and foremost that it's a
skill set that you need to build that
you need to continuously hone in because
channels change tactics change we're
seeing that right now right the things
that were working for us maybe for a
certain type of business works and maybe
doesn't translate as well for a
different one maybe the maturity of the
channel is different from what it was
earlier on in which there's more
low-hanging fruit I mean back to a
Facebook example at the time right that
we were sharing at the beginning while
West but I think the most important
piece is first realizing this is
important and then just spending a lot
of time and energy to try to learn it
and ways of learning it I think this
podcast is a great one actually I've
learned a lot from listening to you guys
interview other practitioners who are
like really deep into trade or ASO I
think this is the most important piece
you know the mindset I'm taking the time
I'm making it a priority because I think
it's easy to get obsessed over product
and product is important of course but
in this day and age like product alone
won't do it and many times a worse
product wins over a better product just
because they have better distribution
right and this whole idea about the
teams versus slack example and the
growth charts are like amazing back to
your question David how do we get this
thing going inside of like so this sleep
product is live it's called rest and if
you want to check it out it's get rest
dot app app and it's live and it has a
mixture of like this audio content I was
telling you it's the largest audio
catalog for falling asleep and going
back to sleep really really fast and
we're building these aips which we're
really excited about and it's in like
Early Access right now and so how do we
get the initial users for that it's a
mixture of cross promotion cross
promotion helps with our existing app
because we already have an audience and
the use case translates so we were able
to target folks at night for example
that's something you don't have the
first time around right we did that at
Elevate coming from mind snacks we've
sent out like a blast or my size list
like hey if you're interested and when
you're in that like zero to one those
little boosts are a big deal totally for
the streamer which we had absolutely
nothing you know going for us no money
no nothing and SEO ended up being the
thing for us long tail SEO was huge so
it just takes time right that takes time
you need to be able to like survive as
that thing kicks in and starts working
and I also do wonder how it's gonna be
now in this world of generative Ai and
search will change SEO will change or
not I don't know but I think it's a
really interesting discussion but yeah
so cross promotion is something we do we
also have money so we have money from
the business so we're able to like buy
users get that going and not to an
insane amount but to a good enough
amount for us to like be able to
understand if your products working get
some metrics right do you consider like
your CAC LTV to be like a product Market
fit indicator I guess I mean if you
wanted to be a viable business it
probably needs a but do you use it I
mean because like you can just purely
use like retention metrics but you also
look at revenue and scalability metrics
I don't know if I look at it like actual
TV like we look at it quite closely just
because we would love to be able to
scale paid acquisition even further and
that's being a constraining factor
because we're not there yet maybe it's
product Market feed and it's the right
term like I just see this needs to work
for this to be viable right do we have a
bio business here or not I don't think
it's totally unindicative of product
Market fit right because business with
product Market fit tend to be good
businesses that's the market part and so
I think it's interesting to look at
earlier though I do see some Founders
like over rotate on it too soon right
well they'll be like trying to balance
that equation right at the beginning
you've been in this long enough you know
like you don't need to necessarily have
a dollar ten for every dollar spent what
matters is learning what matters is it
right yeah and and in my experience like
actual TV thing it's surprisingly hard
like yeah yeah it's not easy and my
conclusion at least so far I guess
consumer world with this type of
products you know you need a big organic
piece to make everything work the core
product has to be good
or virality or whatever it is there
needs to be a really core organic piece
to make the system work at least that's
how it's been in like all of our cases I
think it's a great place to wrap up it
was so fun having you on the podcast and
I I can't wish you had another three
hours to go maybe maybe we should just
do something in the Rogan style four
hours just I mean you have the logo at
the back the the yeah I've already got
it so we're going here I'm telling you
I'm telling you somehow they keep it
going I don't understand how these long
Pockets do it but like we have a lot in
our brains we could talk for hours we do
we could anything you wanted to share as
we wrapped up Martina you're hiring
anything you want to share about your
apps and business as we wrap up just
check out our products and send us
feedback and so it's podcast.app and get
rest that app really curious to see what
you think and we keep on working on both
of them making improvements and trying
to like really finesse them so yeah we'd
love to hear from the audience and get
feedback and also I'm also curious to
learn about New Growth playbooks so if
you have like a growth secret you know
that you send it on one of the Martins
yeah
one to three notes and we can trade my
growth secrets for your growth secrets
I'm always interested in learning I
really consider myself a student of this
discipline and I think this audience is
quite a special one awesome thank you so
much it was great talking to you today
thank you for having me on
thanks so much for listening
if you have a minute please leave a
review in your favorite podcast player
you can also stop by
chat.subclub.com to join our private
community
[Music]